from Ukraine to Gaza the world seems
从乌克兰到加沙，世界似乎比
more divided and uncertain than it's
been for years Global powers and Western
多年来更加分裂和不确定 全球大国和西方
alliances have been put to the test and
联盟都受到了考验，
amid the turmoil China is rising to
在动荡之中，中国崛起
challenge the world order Chinese
挑战世界秩序 中国国家
president Xi Jinping now in his third
主席习近平现已进入第三个
term in office has high ambitions
任期 雄心勃勃
[Music]
领土争端引发了人们对
territorial disputes have sparked fears
可能产生
of a larger conflict that could have
区域和全球影响的更大规模冲突的担忧 你
Regional and Global implications you
已经接近中国 J 附近的水域，
have approached the waters near Chinese
包括南中国海有争议的水域
J including in the contested Waters of
你的诅咒离开并
the South China Sea your curse leave and
让 F 留在威胁所在的台湾地区
keep F over and in Taiwan where the
中国军事入侵的可能性
threat of a Chinese military Invasion
越来越
looms
大，同时在国内对
larger meanwhile at home attacks on
基本自由和人权的攻击也
basic freedoms and human rights have
变得更加严重，就像在新章，
become more severe like in Shin Jang
中国继续严重
where China continues to commit serious
侵犯人权，有人说
human rights abuses some say a genocide
对贫穷的穆斯林进行种族灭绝，那么
against the weager Muslims so how far
中国的独裁愿景能达到多远
will China's autocratic Vision reach and
与西方长期酝酿的紧张关系会
will long simmering tension with the
达到沸点吗？
West hit a boiling
我是 M Hassen，我来到
point I'm M Hassen and I've come here to
伦敦传奇的康威大厅，
London's legendary Conway Hall to go
与 Victor gal 进行正面交锋，他是
head-to-head with Victor gal he's vice
中国与全球化中心的副总裁。
president of of the center for China and
北京，
globalization in Beijing former
已故中国领导人邓小平的前翻译，
interpreter for the late Chinese leader
Deng shiao ping and a proud defender of
中华人民共和国的自豪捍卫者。今晚我将向他询问
the People's Republic I'll ask him about
中国的全球野心及其对
China's Global Ambitions and its
人权和公民自由的侵略性镇压。
aggressive Crackdown on human rights and
civil
liberties tonight I'll also be joined by
三位专家史蒂芬·陈也将加入其中。
three experts Steven Chan a professor at
伦敦大学
the University of London's School of
东方与非洲研究学院教授拉汉·阿萨德（Rahan Assad），
Oriental and African studies rahan Assad
韦尔遗产（weer Heritage）人权律师，马丁·杰克（
a human rights lawyer of weer Heritage
Martin Jake），《
and Martin Jake author of the bestseller
当中国统治世界》一书的作者，
when China rules the world and a
political commentator on
中国政治评论员维克多·盖尔（Victor gal），非常感谢您
[Music]
加入我的行列。 今晚
[Applause]
在伦敦进行面对面的交流，谢谢你的邀请，
China Victor gal thank you so much for
中国增加了军费开支，
joining me on head-to head this evening
正在扩大核武库，
here in London thank you for having me
现在拥有世界上最大的海军，
China has upped its military spending
中国国家主席习近平表示，中国
it's expanding its nuclear Arsenal it
的军队应该有
now has the biggest Navy in the world
能力进行战斗 打赢
Chinese president Xi Jinping has said
战争，告诉军队集中
that the country's military should be
精力打仗，提高
capable of quote fighting and winning
打赢的能力，你想
wars and told the military to focus all
打谁，你想赢谁，
your energy on fighting improve your
首先中国的
capability to win Victor who do you want
军费是
to fight and who do you want to win
世界第二，但它 只是美国的一小部分，
against first of all the Chinese
而且中国的地缘
military spending is the second largest
政治形势非常困难，
in the world but it is only a fraction
中国总共有14个陆地国家和
of that of the United States and China
邻国，还有
has a very uh difficult geopolitical
6个海洋国家，
situation China has 14 land and
所以中国的防御
neighboring countries all together and
本质上不是为了与任何人作战，除了
six Maritime Nations uh for China
那些想要的人之外。 入侵中国或
therefore China's defense defensive in
对中国发动战争 中国的
nature is not for fighting anyone except
军费开支是为了和平
those who want to invade China or to
而不是战争，战争将强加于
launch a war against China China's
中国，中国需要反击 你
military spending is for peace rather
说这是为了和平，但你的邻居
than war and War will be forced upon
不同意 你的邻居非常
China and China need to fight back you
担心
say it's for peace but your neighbors
日本已经拉响警报，称
don't agree your neighbors are pretty
你们的军力建设对他们来说非常严重，
worried about you you go through the
印度担心
list Japan has sounded the alarm saying
中国在其边境地区，菲律宾
your military buildup is very serious
总统警告说，中国正在
concern to them India is worried about
成为一个更加明显和令人担忧的
China on its border and the Philippines
威胁，他说这些是
president has warned that China is
代表
becoming a more pronounced and worrisome
亚洲超过16亿人民的国家的民选政府 这
threat he says those are the elected
不是美国 这不是
governments of countries representing
西方 这是亚洲邻国说
over 1.6 billion people in Asia this is
我们担心中国 你可能会
not the United States this is not the
提到
West this is Asian neighbors saying
中国的三个邻国 呃，让我们谈谈
we're worried about China may you
其中之一 他们每个人都
mentioned the three of the neighboring
很快，日本在1945年
countries of China uh let's talk about
不仅向
one of them one each of them very
美国而且向中国无条件投降，
quickly Japan unconditionally
如果你仔细阅读
surrendered not only to the United
States but also to China in
日本签署的无条件投降文件，那么你就会知道
1945 and if you read very carefully the
日本需要如何处理其外交
unconditional surrender document that
事务以及 它的军队
Japan signed then you will know how
呃与中国以及
Japan need to conduct its foreign
日本无条件
affairs as well as its military troops
投降的所有国家有关，因为印度是一个伟大的国家，
uh with China and with all those
countries that Japan unconditionally
中国和印度之间存在领土争端，但这种争端
surrendered for India is a great nation
不是中国造成的，也不是
and there is a territorial dispute
印度造成的，它是被创造或留下的
between China and India but that dispute
落后于英属印度呃
was not created by China neither was it
政府，这是一个伟大的历史教训，
created by India it was created or left
但现在中国在24年国防
behind by the British Indian uh
开支增长了7%，是
government that's great history lesson
5年来最多的，你已经连续29年
but right now China in 24 the defense
军费增长是
spending is going up by 7% the most for
世界上任何国家中最多的 自2022年以来，
5 years you've had 29 consecutive years
中国增加了在
of military expenditure growth the most
台湾周围的军事演习，自5月台湾
of any country in the world since 2022
新总统就职以来，这种演习升级了，
China has increased military drills
自那以后，中国不再喜欢他了，
around Taiwan it's escalated since the
几乎每天都有
new Taiwanese president was inaugurated
涉及中国军舰、无人机
in May China is not a fan of him since
对台湾进行网络攻击的活动，中国正
then there's been almost daily activity
准备入侵台湾 难道
involving China's warships drones cyber
只有一个中国吗？台湾是中国的一部分，
attacks against Taiwan China is getting
中华人民共和国政府
ready to invade Taiwan isn't it there is
是
only one China Taiwan is part of China
全中国的唯一合法政府，
and the government of the People's
Republic of China is the sole legitimate
台湾国家双方之间的确切地位是未结束的内战。
government for the totality of China the
exact status between the two sides of
1949年，所以自
the Taiwan state is The Unfinished Civil
20世纪80年代初以来，中国不想用战争
War back in
来解决这个统一问题，你
1949 so ever since the beginning of the
不想用战争，但你
1980s China does not want to use a war
用舰船、无人机、网络攻击包围它，
to solve this unification problem you
每次都发出很多威胁
don't want to use a war but you're
台湾分裂分子想要
surrounding it with ships drones cyber
突破极限，他们
attacks and making lots of threats each
将看到越来越多的
time when the separatists in Taiwan want
to push the edge of the envelope they
中华民族致力于最终实现
will come across more and more
和平统一的承诺，否则
demonstration of the commitment of the
这就是你的
Chinese Nation to eventually achieve
国防部长说的对任何胆敢追求
peaceful reunification or otherwise
台独的人的愚蠢考验 将被粉碎
that's the lious test your defense
成碎片并面临毁灭，
minister said anyone who dares to pursue
这听起来像是一个真正和平的人，这是一个真实的
independence for Taiwan will be crushed
声明，因为如果
into pieces and face destruction sounds
分离主义者真的想在某个大国
like a truly peaceful guy that's a real
的帮助下将P置于信封的边缘，
statement because if the separatists if
例如想要
the separatists really want to put P the
利用台湾作为 充当其
edge of the envelope with the aid of
与中国地缘政治竞争的代理人，然后
some big country for example which wants
等着看会发生什么，
to use Taiwan as a proxy in its own
统一将会实现，中国
geopolitical rivalry against China then
是联合国安理会常任理事国中唯一
wait until you see what will happen
reunification will be achieved and China
尚未实现完全
is the only permanent member of the
统一的我就是我我” 我总是
United Nations security Council which
对“统一”这个词感到好笑，
has not yet achieved a complete
因为如果这是一个中国，显然
reunification what I'm what I I'm always
它不是一个中国，那么
amused with this phrase reunification
根据定义你就接受了，如果你需要
because if it's one China that clearly
统一，他们正在做他们自己的
it's not One China clearly you're
事情，以及为什么对台湾如此痴迷，
accepting by definition if you need to
你是一个拥有370万人口的国家
reunify it they are doing their own
平方英里 人口 是
thing and why this obsession with Taiwan
台湾经济的60倍 面积是台湾的20倍
you are a country of 3.7 million square
你为什么痴迷于台湾
miles a population 60 times that of
为什么不放过他们呢 为了
Taiwan economy 20 times the size of
捍卫中国的主权和
Taiwan why are you obsessed with Taiwan
领土完整 任何一寸土地
why not just leave them be in terms of
都不是一寸太多
Defending China's sovereignty and
人不是一个人太多，所以
territorial Integrity any inch of land
我们需要实现统一，
is not one inch too much any one single
即使他们不想成为
person is not one one person too many so
你们国家的一部分，12%的台湾人
we need to achieve reunification as even
说他们想与中国统一，
though they don't want to be part of
12%你不能得到更多 不受欢迎的原因是，
your country 12% of the people of Taiwan
say they want to reunify with China
一个中国政策不应该由台湾人民来决定，
12% you can't get more unpopular than
你非常直言不讳，
that in thaty it's not up to the people
无视人民的观点、自由和
in Taiwan to decide about the one China
尊严，你说你不关心
policy you're very blunt in your
他们认为你在一份声明中也说过的话。
disregard for people's views freedoms
法国报纸《柠檬》的采访
dignity you say that you don't care
一旦我们收回岛屿，我们就
about what they think you also said in
必须询问每个人的出身，那些
an interview with the French newspaper
有日本血统的人，你基本上
lemond once we get the island back we'll
说他们占人口的10%，
have to ask everyone's Origins those who
必须宣誓效忠
have Japanese ancestry who you basicly
统一，否则
say cons constitute 10% of the
就会有 为了帮助他们离开，你
population will have to pledge loyalty
基本上是在呼吁对台湾
to reunification and writing otherwise
230万人民进行种族清洗，
will'll have to help them leave you're
不，你还记得
basically calling for the ethnic
1945年，当时日本无条件
cleansing of 2.3 million people in
投降了很多
Taiwan no you remember back in
来自日本的台湾人，他们
1945 when Japan unconditionally
当时是呃台湾的统治者 他们
surrendered a lot of people in Taiwan
留下来是因为
who originally came from Japan they were
中华民族的宽容，几
the rulers of uh Taiwan at the time they
十年后，他们
stay behind because of the magnanimity
现在占台湾当地人口的10%左右，如果
of the Chinese Nation now several
你认真做功课，你会
decades later they account for about 10%
发现那些顽固的台湾
of the local population in Taiwan now if
分裂分子包括许多
you really do your homework you will
日本人，但好吧 但你会
realize that those Die Hard Taiwanese
摆脱他们，你就会摆脱230万人，
separatists include many of these
不，统一后，
Japanese but okay but you would get rid
台湾每个人都需要做出承诺，
of them you would get rid of 2.3 million
是否承认只有
people no after the reunification
一个中国，台湾是中国的一部分，
everyone in Taiwan need to make a pledge
如果他们不做出承诺 他们
whether they acknowledge there is only
是那些对
one China and Taiwan is part of China
中国政策发誓的人，他们是当地人，你没有
and if they don't make that pledge they
说你
us those who pledge wow for the one
所说的每个人都有日本血统，这
China policy they are local you didn't
实际上是种族的，你
by the way you didn't say everyone you
根据他们的民族传统来挑选人，让他们
said of Japanese descent that is
忠诚 测试，否则他们必须
literally ethnical you're picking people
离开他们所在的国家，这不是
by their ethnic Heritage making them do
忠诚度测试，例如在英国，
a loyalty test otherwise they have to
如果你是英国公民，你需要
get out of the country they've is not a
支持君主制，你不能说我不，
loyalty test here for example in Britain
我站在英国不支持
if you are a British citizen you need to
君主制 我不喜欢查尔斯国王
support the monarchy you cannot say I no
不，你不能说不 我只是这么说 我
I'm standing in Britain don't support
真的只是这么说 你不能采取
the monarchy I don't like King Charles
任何行动反对君主制
no you cannot say no I just said it m I
但我不必签署一份保证书说
literally just said it you cannot take
我很好地支持查尔斯国王 每个国家
any action to oppose the monarchy system
都是不同的，我们谈论的是中国，
but I don't have to sign a pledge saying
中国是非常不同的，中国有一项政策，
I support King Charles well each country
这是宪法的一部分，
is different we are talking about China
涉及那些不想
China is very and China has one policy
成为你们国家一部分的台湾人，让我们
which is part of the Constitution
请来我们的小组，他们正在等待进来，
involves people in Taiwan who don't want
加入，让我们看看他们的想法 我是
to be part of your country let's bring
in our panel who are waiting to come in
伦敦大学
and join let's see what they think I'm
东方与非洲研究学院的 Steven uh Chan 教授加入的，嗯，如果
joined by Steven uh Chan professor at
你今天在台湾，
the University of London School of
你对迫在眉睫的入侵有多担心 我
Oriental and African studies um if
今天不在台湾 我 明年我要去台湾，
you're in Taiwan today how worried are
我已经去过
you about Al looming Invasion I'm not in
台湾所有大城市五次了，
Taiwan today I'm going to be visiting
我注意到最明显的是，与
next year I've been there five times in
我交谈过的人中，没有人
all of the great cities of Taiwan and
因为他们的感觉而想要重新加入或与中国统一。
what I've noticed most conspicuously is
that nobody I've talked to wants to
rejoin or reunify with China because of
所以我认为，如果
their sense of freedom and their sense
你要说我们的主权比
of
你对
self-determination so I think that if
自决和自由的渴望更重要，那么
you're going to say our sovereignty
你所做的事情不会
matters more than your desire for your
让你在台湾受欢迎， 你不会
own self-determination and freedom then
赢得中国对该岛主权的争论
you're doing something that will not
马丁呃 马丁·杰克斯和
make you popular in Taiwan and you won't
我们在一起
win the argument for Chinese sovereignty
畅销书《当中国统治
over the island Martin uh Martin Jakes
世界》的作者 马丁 你过去说过，
is here with us author of the
不能
bestselling book when China rules the
仅仅通过西方来看待中国 所以我和我
world Martin you've said in the past
同意你的观点，那里有问题，
that China cannot should not be seen
但我在节目开始时问维克多
through a solely Western lens so I and I
有关日本、印度和
agree with you and there's issues there
菲律宾分裂台湾的问题，只是
but I began the show by asking Victor
该地区的问题，你认为中国
about Japan and India and the
应对其中一些问题负责
Philippines separate Taiwan just the
所有这些问题 这些问题都不是，
issues in the region do you think China
中国显然
is responsible for some of those issues
不可避免地卷入了所有这些问题，嗯，我
all of those issues none of those issues
认为，呃，实际上，如果你看看
well China is obviously involved in
中国过去的崛起，你就会
inevitably in all of those issues um I
知道，这是我们历史上见过的 30 40 年来最大的巨大
think that uh that actually if you look
变化
at the rise of China over the last you
呃，不可避免地，这正在改变
know 30 40 years spectacular biggest
世界上该地区的一切，呃，但这并
change we've ever seen in history really
没有，但
and uh inevitably that is changing
我要说的关于中国R的值得注意的事情是你如何
everything in the region in the world uh
引用军事数据等等，
that doesn't but the remarkable thing
但中国自1979年以来没有打过任何战争，
I'd say Med about China's R is how you
如果 你将其与处于
quoted the military figures and so on
同一发展阶段的美国、欧洲、日本进行比较，
but China has not fought any wars since
他们
1979 if you compare that with America
非常激进，嗯，让我们谈谈
Europe Japan at the same stage of
人权吧，维克多，你在
development they were they were
中国的新江省称之为赌注，你的兄弟
extremely aggressive um let's talk human
姐妹们，你对
rights Victor you've called Wagers in
至少一半的事实有何感想？ 有人
China's shinjang Province your brothers
说你的兄弟姐妹有更多人被
and sisters how do you feel about the
fact that at least half a million some
中国政府关押在难民营里，占
say more of your brothers and sisters
成年贫困人口的 5% 是
are being detained in camps by the
Chinese government that's 5% % of the
世界上监狱拘留率最高的国家之一 地中海维格尔人是自豪的
adult weager population one of the
民族
highest imprisonment detention rates in
56 个民族之一 在中国，
the world Med the weagles are proud
就我而言，Wiggles 是我
ethnic group one of the
真正的兄弟姐妹，我认识他们中的许多人，
56 ethnic nationalities in China The
我定期去 Shin Jang，
Wiggles as far as I'm concerned are my
如果有人
true brothers and sisters I know many of
认真指责中国
them I travel to Shin Jang regularly and
在正义中实行大规模群众活动，我现在会与许多其他 Wigos 交谈。
I talk to many other wigos now if anyone
weagles给了我证据，我想
is serious about accusing China of
人权观察组织说过，
practicing mass in Justice to the
近年来有50万人被拘留，
weagles give me the evidence I think
你一直引用
just did Human Rights Watch say half a
人权观察组织的话，我告诉你你知道他们从
million people detained over the years
哪里得到这些数字吗？我
in recent years you keep quote Human
不知道我可以吗？ 告诉你，我不知道，
Rights Watch and I tell you do you know
我以为你是新庄的专家，
where they got those numbers from I
你和韦格斯谈过，你从来
don't know can I tell you I I don't know
没有听说过这些数字，我不知道
I thought you were the exper you to
他们从哪里得到消息来源，所以他们的消息
shinjang you've spoken to wegers you
来源是新庄高人民
never heard these numbers I do not know
检察院呃，它已经发表了
where did they get the source so their
新江官方机构自己的统计数据
source is the shinjang high people's
称，自 2017 年以来，该地区有 54 名被定罪的人，4,826 人
procurator uh which has published its
被起诉。
own statistics shinjang official body
联合国人权办公室
which says it's convicted 54 4,826
查看了卫星录像，他们
people prosecuted in the region since
说，大赦国际估计人口的 10% 至 20%，
2017 the United Nations office for human
难民营中有 100 万人，其中 50
rights looked at satellite footage they
万人是 一个保守的数字，很多，
say 10 to 20% of the population amnesty
如果你打电话给那个组织，请放心，
estimates a million people in camps half
那个组织
a million is a conservative number many
已经因为
if you called that organization please
他们的虚假信息而完全失去信誉，所以我
be assured that that organization has
喜欢我们正在玩的这个游戏，你
been completely discredited for the
给我一个来源，我给你一个来源，
false information they every so this I
他们已经失去信誉了 他们
love this game we're playing you give
说谎，我怎么能问你一个
give me a source I give you a source
问题，有多少人被
they're discredited they've said
拘留在新江，你给我一个
falsehoods how can let me ask you a
号码，听着，如果你看，你给
question how many people are in
我一个号码，如果你看，我
detention in shinjang you give me a
没有号码，为什么不呢？ 等一下，你
number listen if you look at sh you give
不能说这不是五十万，
me a number if you look and I do not
然后说你没有号码，我有
have the number why not yeah hold on you
一个号码，我有消息来源，
can't say it's not half a million and
你认为有多少人，让我给你我的
then say you don't have a number I have
理由，不，我经常去 Shinjang 我
a number I have sources how many people
几乎和你的兄弟姐妹一起旅行，
do you think a det let me give you my
你经常去那里，但你不能告诉我有
reason no I go to shinjang a lot I
多少人被拘留，听
travel almost your brothers and sisters
他们更快乐，他们享受生活，
you go there a lot but you can't tell me
他们享受穆斯林的习俗和
how many people are in detention listen
传统，听听有多少人被
they are happier they enjoy their life
拘留，维克多让 我要
they enjoy their Muslim practice and
哲学一点 不，不要哲学一点，
traditions listen how many people are in
用数字来说明 有多少人被
detention Victor many let me be
拘留 你说不 不 五
philosophical no don't be philosophical
十万怎么样 好吧 让我们二十
be numerical how many people are in
五万 让我让我让我完成我的
detention you said not to no to half a
观点 不 如果你回答这个问题
million how about okay let's quarter of
你 不能在节目中对维克多进行阻挠，
a million let me let me let me finish my
任何人都认为他们
point nope if you answer the question
会独立，他们中
you can't filibuster Victor on the show
有多少人出庭，有多少人被拘留，这是
anyone many do think Independence they
极少数，所以你没有一个
will be dwelt with in how many of them
数字，你说他们都很高兴，但是 你
are in court and how many detention the
不会让独立调查人员进来，你
very small minority so you don't have a
不会让记者去那里，
number you say they're all happy but you
为什么不去那里，我很乐意护送
won't let in dependent investigators you
你去靖江，真的，我可以做出这个
won't letting journalists to go there
承诺，我会与中国
why not there I will be happy to escort
政府交谈，这就是问题，中国人，我
you to Jing Jang really I can make that
不知道。 不需要护送 我不需要监护人 我
promise I will speak to the Chinese
想要自由地走 你能允许我
government here's the problem Chinese I
不做那个决定 哦，
don't want escort I don't want minders I
刚才你要做出各种各样的
want to go freely will you allow that I
打断 突然我说让我
do not made that decision oh a moment
自由地走 自由地与韦斯说话 可以 我
ago you were going to make all sorts of
这样做，没有任何人的照顾，没有中国
interruptions suddenly I said let me go
政府的护送，我很乐意为
freely and speak to weas freely can I do
你辩护，哦，刚才你说
that with no minders no Chinese
你会组织它，现在我们要提出一个
government escort I will be happy to
你不能保证的案件，拉汉·阿萨德
make your case oh just now you said
是该机构的高级研究员。 大西洋
you'd organize it now we're about make a
理事会国际人权
case you can't guarantee uh rahan Assad
律师，你是个弱者，呃，维克多
is a senior fellow at the Atlantic
说兄弟姐妹，你的兄弟姐妹
Council international human rights
lawyer you are a weager uh who Victor
自 2016 年以来一直被关在新江的拘留营里，我相信
says brothers and sisters your literal
拉汉告诉我们你兄弟发生了什么事，
brother has been held in an internment
以及你对维克多的回应是
camp in shinjang since 2016 I believe
什么 你听说过，
rahan tell us what happened to your
如果你不
brother and what is your response to
介意与我们分享的话，你兄弟的最新消息是的，我的兄弟
Victor to what you've heard and what is
阿克巴尔·阿萨德是一位著名的科技
the latest on your brother if you don't
企业家，事实上，你自己的媒体在
mind sharing with us yeah my brother
Akbar Assad is a prominent Tech
他被拘留之前称他为科技界的明星。
entrepreneur in fact your own media
被邀请参加加拉国宴，
Outlet called him bright star in the
然后他就消失了，你怎么
tech world right before his detention he
解释
was invited on a state Galla dinner and
现在M再说一次，在中国，我们有大约20个
then he disappeared how could you
穆斯林民族，你需要问一个
explain
问题，为什么极端主义
now M again in China we have about 20
主要存在于wial社区，
Muslim ethnic groups you need to ask one
因为wigo社区中有极端分子
question why the extremism existed
那些想把申
mostly among the wial communities
张和你兄弟分开的人 被
because there are extremists among the
中央情报局和
wigo community who want to separate Shin
其他西方
Jang away from your brother been
组织支持的任何人定罪 这是事实 坚持与
convicted of any supported by CIA and
他们不支持的哈扎克交谈
other Western
你的兄弟是否被定罪
organizations that's the real truth hold
根据联合国的说法，没有
on talk to the hazaks they don't support
审判已经进行，他只是被强行
has your brother been convicted of a
失踪，实际上这相当于
crime um according to un there's no
强制失踪，但根据
trial has taken place he just forcibly
中国政府的说法，他犯有
disappeared actually it amount the en
煽动民族歧视罪，同时
Force disappearance but according to the
他受到系统性的压迫，当
Chinese government he committed a crime
我对这一决定提出质疑时，因为
of inciting ethnic discrimination while
根据中国法律，如果你
he's a systematically oppressed and when
I challenge that decision because under
你犯了被指控的罪行，你被判了三年徒刑，但
under the Chinese law if you're
他被判了 15 年徒刑，你如何证明他们的
committed with the alleged crime that
犯罪行为是正当的，那么
you you have three years sentences but
你如何解释这是一个
he got 15 years how do you in justify
法治体系，你提到如果人们
that then they switch the crime so how
不支持- 独立 那么他们
do you even explain this is a rule of
在新江就很好 我哥哥一点也不
law system you mentioned that if people
支持独立 事实上你的媒体
are not pro- independent then they're
看到每日媒体邀请他
fine in shinjang my brother by no means
交换信息
is pro- independent in fact your media
他访问北京时是否分裂了国家 你对
Outlet sees daily media invited him to
她哥哥M在
exchange information did he split the
前面的待遇还满意吗 让我在这个奥古斯托机构中
country when he visited beij you okay
提出几个非常简短的观点，
with the treatment of her brother M in
一些威戈人所涉及的真正罪行
front of this very Augusto body let me
正在煽动新
make several very brief points the real
江独立，他们违反了一个中国
crime involved by some of the wigo
政策现在与你
people are agitating for shinjang
知道的不同社区分开，可能会发现
Independence they violate the one China
自己不同的问题 需要
policy Now set separate from that you
通过法律来解决，
know different communities May F find
我希望，但是我们的兄弟已经被拘留了
their own different problems which need
八年了，我不知道具体
to be sorted out in the cuse of Law and
情况，我希望我能帮助你真正审视针对
I hope but our brother's been detained
for eight years well I did not know the
他的指控的案件，我希望你的兄弟是
ch I hope I can help you to really look
如果
at the case at the accusation against
是这样的话，就让法律把
him I hope your brother is not guilty of
它的CA带走吧，你们的媒体称
inciting for separatism of Shing Jang if
他为模范公民，是民族团结的促进者。
that is the case then let the law take
你能和
its CA well your media out that called
你的兄弟或人谈谈吗？ 不，完全
him a model citizen who is a promoter of
不像你知道的那样，他被
ethnic unity in sh have you been able to
强行失踪了八年，
speak to your brother or no not at all
直到上个月我父母第一次
like you know for eight years he's
见到他，这是什么样的司法
forcibly disappeared um up until like
系统，你在嘲笑你，
last months for the first time my
你不仅仅是拘留他们，维克多，
parents saw him what kind of justice
他们” 正在遭受酷刑
system is that you're making a mockery
联合国收集的无数证词 你
you're not just detaining them Victor
同意吗 M 当你谈论
they're being tortured numerous
酷刑时 想想关塔那摩湾
testimonies the UN has collected are you
监狱 哦，我的话，而不是在 Shin
okay with that M when you talk about
Jang Shin Jang 是一个非常和平
torture think about Guantanamo Bay
与
prison oh my word rather than in Shin
稳定的地方 对 Victor 来说是被
Jang Shin Jang is a place of great peace
拘留者的叙述 包括被绑
and
在
stability hold on Victor the accounts of
南加州老虎身上用电击棒殴打 ch
detainees include being beaten with
158 被泼水审讯
Batts electric Batts while strapped in a
So-Cal tiger ch
长时间单独监禁 被迫
158 being subjected to interrogation
长时间坐在凳子上
with water poured on their faces
像这样 你没关系，
prolonged solitary confinement forced to
这就是 骄傲的中国，也许你正在
sit motionless on stools for long
读美国士兵在伊拉克犯下的案件，
periods like this you're okay with this
我正在读
this is the proud China probably you are
2022年8月从新
reading the case in Iraq committed by
章集中营出来的被拘留者的美国报告，你们是
the American solders I'm reading the U
兄弟姐妹，但这些兄弟
report in August 2022 from detainees who
姐妹，你们不是 似乎很在乎你
came out of camps in Shin Jang you're
怎么知道
brothers and sisters but these brothers
伊拉克发生过任何酷刑，出于兴趣我知道我
and sisters you don't seem to give a
怎么知道我是如何与
damn about how do you know any torture
伊拉克驻北京大使交谈的，好吧，他
happened in Iraq out of Interest I know
在我面前哭了，我确信兰的
how I know for sure how I talked to the
父母也哭了 你似乎并不
Iraqi Ambassador in Beijing okay he wept
关心，我希望你会告诉你的
in front of me and I'm sure Ran's
兄弟，成为一项对华政策的坚定支持者，
parents have wept and you don't seem to
成为一个自豪的
care and I hope you will tell your
中国人，她不能告诉他，因为她不能和
brother be a staunch supporter of one
他说话，因为你拒绝访问
China policy be a proud
维克多·维克多，她可以 不要和他说话，
Chinese she can't tell him cuz she can't
你要安排吗？你
speak to him because you deny access
现在要安排一次拜访吗？我很乐意帮
Victor Victor she can't speak to him are
你打个电话，
you going to arrange it are you going to
这里已经做出了很多承诺，伙计们，你应该
arrange a visit now I'd be happy to help
呃跟进这个办公室。 所有
you make a phone call there's a lot of
见证人，我们都是见证人，确实让我把
promises being made here guys you should
马丁带进来，杰克·马丁，当你
uh follow up on this office you are all
听到人们说基本上没有
Witnesses we Are Witnesses indeed let me
酷刑，每个人都在编造，没有
bring in Martin Jake Martin when you
人被拘留，来吧，这太
hear people say basically there's no
荒谬了，马丁不是很好吗？我的意思是
torture everyone's making it up there's
我不知道所有细节
nobody in detention come on that's
新庄的情况很明显，但很明显，
ridiculous is it not Martin well I mean
I don't know all the details of the
新庄长期以来在
situation in ch Shin Jang but clearly
河与汉之间的关系方面存在一个大问题，
there's been a big problem for a long
2009 年
time in Shin Jang in terms of the
发生示威并造成 200
relationship between the weer and the
人死亡时，这一问题达到了顶峰。 那时
Han and that came to a head in 2009
中国人对中国造成了同样
when there was a demonstration and 200
的损害，所以这不是
people were killed by by the weer then
这，在我看来，这是一个很深的问题，
the Chinese Chinese inflicted the same
而且不容易被忽视。
kind of damage on the so this is not
中国没有其他
this is this is a deep problem in my
类似的问题，是的，但人们认为
view and it's not easily passed up
这是一个 相当大的问题，这对他们来说是一个非常
there's no other problem in China of
大的问题，是的，我做的
this kind yeah but people consider
另一件事是，我想说的是，嗯嗯，
that's a pretty big problem it's a very
关于
big problem for them yeah and I do the
分离主义的观点是正确的，我认为
other thing bet I'd say is that um um
中国的 3000 万穆斯林是
the point that's being made about
他们拥有最大的单一少数派，
separatism is true that I think that
他们完全融合在一起，但
what the 30 million Muslims in China the
问题是 Shin Jang
ha is the biggest single minority they
显然是分离主义问题 斯蒂芬
have they are completely integrated but
让我问你这个问题 维克多
the problem the problem is shin Jang is
今晚做出了很多承诺，关于
clearly the issue of separatism Stephen
我去 Shinjang 和 Rean 去
let me ask you this question Victor's
Shin 每个人都会去
making a lot of promises tonight about
好吧，你
me going to shinjang and rean going to
去中国有多安全，你觉得
Shin everyone's going to be
你去中国有多自由，当我
fine how how safe how okay are you with
去中国时，我已经有一段时间没有去过了，
visiting China how how free do you think
我几乎被监视了
you are when you go to China when I go
247，总有一个人我可以 位置
to China and I haven't been for some
跟踪着我，所以我知道当我的酒店房间
time I'm watched almost
突然升级为宽敞的套房时，
247 there's always someone I can spot is
我现在所处的地方有窃听器，所以
trailing me so I know when my hotel room
is upgraded suddenly to a spacious Suite
像我这样温和批评家和学术批评家的人
I'm now in a place which is bugged so
在中国感觉不安全，相比之下我
someone who's a mild critic and a
当你听到史蒂文说他不觉得安全时，伊万·维克多（iwan Victor）及时感到更
scholarly critic like me doesn't feel
安全，
safe in China by contrast I feel safer
当我们谈论言论自由时，去中国更喜欢去台湾，
in time iwan Victor when you hear Steven
例如
say he doesn't feel that safe going to
在中国，我住在美利坚合众国，
China prefers going to Taiwan when we
我可以说唐纳德
talk about freedom of speech for example
特朗普是一个我不知道假设的
in China I live in the United States of
America where I can say that Donald
自恋者，我也住在英国，
Trump is a I don't know hypothetically
我是英国人，你有里希·苏纳克，
an orang faed
前首相被
narcissist I also live here in the UK
一位劳工
I'm British here you have Rishi sunak
政客称为“失败者”，嗯，中国没有人这样认为
the former prime minister was called a
一种可怕的自由，以这种方式谈论
pints siiz Loser by a labor
他们的政府，谈论
politician um no one in China has that
习近平主席，你不能说
kind of fright freedom to talk about
这样的话，你不敢说
their government to talk about President
这样的话，因为你知道
Xi Jinping in that way you can't say
当你回家时会发生什么，你
anything like you wouldn't dare say
知道会发生什么 发生在你家人身上的事情就是
anything like that because you know what
中国M如果你做
will happen to you when you go home you
任何事写任何电子邮件或与
know what will happen to your family
你的朋友聊天关于采取任何行动
that's what China is M if you do
反对比方说英国首相
anything write anything email or chat to
美国总统
your friends about taking any action
你很快就会和维克多住在一起
against let's say prime minister of
你是一个主人 我说的不是我
Britain president of the United States
所说的，我所说的被称为小失败者，
you'll be dwelt with swiftly Victor
你会称习近平为小失败者吗？
you're a master of not what I said I
每个国家在英国都有不同的
said was called a pint-sized loser would
敏感性，所以你承认
you call Xi Jinping a pint-sized loser
你不能批评中国
many each country has different
政府不不不你可以
sensitivities in UK so you're admitting
如果你是积极的，
you can't criticize the Chinese
你可以批评政府，如果
government no no no you can criticize
你是积极的，你可以批评政府，如果你是新的
the government if you are positive inity
哲学，不，如果你能想出
you can criticize the government if
你的，你必须想出很好的
you're positive is that the new
侮辱，那么建设性的建议，
philosophy no if you can come up with
建设性的建议，例如在
your you got to come up with nice
处理问题上 随着人口老龄化，
insults no what then constructive advice
政府应该做什么，
constructive advice for example in
这位州长应该做什么，但你不能
dealing with a aging population what
说总统撒了谎，他是个骗子，
should be the government do what should
你很快就会
this governor should do but you can't
在中国成为德瓦尔特，你不能说
say the president's lied he's a liar
这是你最诚实的事情。 我们
nothing you will be DeWalt with very
说过今晚呃维克多女孩我们
swiftly in China you cannot say that
要休息一下，第一部分是
that is the most honest thing you've
与我们的嘉宾受害者对战，第二
said tonight uh Victor gal we're going
部分我们将讨论
to take a break that's part one of
习近平主席，我们将讨论
head-to-head with our guest vict to gal
独裁统治，
in part two we'll be talking about
我们将在伦敦康威大厅听到我们非常耐心的
President Xi Jinping we'll be talking
听众的声音，
about the issue of dictatorship and
欢迎回到半岛
we'll hear from our very patient
英语频道，本周我的嘉宾是维克多·盖尔（Victor Gal），
audience here in London's Conway Hall
已故中国领导人的前翻译
[Music]
邓少平
[Applause]
该中心的副总裁 北京的中国和全球化
welcome back to head-to-head on Al jazer
以及中华人民共和国的热心推动者，
English my guest this week is Victor gal
former interpreter to the late Chinese
伦敦康威厅的专家小组
leader Den Shao ping vice president of
和现场观众也加入了我们的行列，
the center for China and globalization
in Beijing and an Ardent promoter of the
在 2019 年与观众见面之前，我们很快就会听到维克多的讲话 在这个
People's Republic we're also joined by
节目中，我问了一个问题，她正在
an expert panel here in London's Conway
准备成为《生活
Hall and a live audience who we're going
独裁者》的总统吗？我的意思是，他是自
to hear from shortly Victor before we
马云以来中国最有权势的领导人，他
get to the audience in 2019 on this very
废除了国家主席任期限制，他
show I asked the question is she being
现在已经是总统的第三个五年任期了，
gearing up to be president for Life
所以我 今晚再问一次，
dictator in Chief I mean he's the most
他现在是终身主席吗？是一个真正的
powerful leader of China since Ma he's
独裁者吗？首先，
abolished presidential term limits he's
中国国家主席习近平永远不会
now in his third five-year term as
担任终身主席，会有一个
president so I'll ask again tonight is
时间限制，届时将
he now president for Life a true
根据中国的法律制度处理 其次，
dictator for the record first of all
Chinese president XI jining will never
中国没有独裁者，为什么
be president for Life there will be a
独裁根本行不通？
time limit when it will be will be
民主意味着现代化，如果你有独裁或独裁统治，
handled according to the Chinese legal
你如何解释
system and Constitution secondly there
中国过去45年发生的深刻转变？
is no dictator in China why because
dictatorship simply doesn't work
democracy means modernization and how
融入一个团队，
can you explain profound transformation
团队合作将比
of China over the past 45 years in China
个人主义重要得多维克多也许前任
if you have dictatorship or
总统也许是张扎民或胡因
authoritarian rule no every leader in
大家都知道习平拥有集中
China will be put into a team and
权力统一权力摆脱了任期
teamwork will be much more important
限制你说有办法摆脱
than individualism Victor maybe previous
他但没有' 实际上没有合法的
president did maybe Jang zamin or huin
方法可以除掉他，他终身掌权
everyone knows xiin ping has centralized
，他喜欢当独裁者，
power Consolidated power got rid of term
我们为什么要假装让我提醒
limits you say there's a way to get rid
你，中国共产党
of him but there isn't actually a legal
是中国的执政党，有
way to get rid of him he's in power for
多达 100 名党员 百万人口，
life and he likes being a dictator why
结构良好，每个省
are we pretending Med allow me to remind
每个国有企业等都
you the Communist Party of China which
会有一个部分小组，
is the ruling party of China has a
membership of up to 100 million people
中国共产党内部没有分裂或辩论，听我说，
it's well structured every Province
中国没有一个人可以对
every state owned Enterprise Etc will
14亿人口和1
have a part cell
亿党员发号施令
there's no division or debate within the
中国共产党好吧，让我们测试一下
Chinese Communist Party listen to me no
这是一项不可能完成的任务让我们测试一下
single person in China can dictate to a
这个命题总统去年赢得了
population of 1.4 billion people and 100
投票赢得了投票我将其放在
million membership of the Communist
空中引号中你知道
Party of China okay let's test that
去年有利于习近平的总统票数吗
that's a mission impossible Let's test
全国人民
that proposition the president won a
代表大会是这个结构的一部分，你刚刚
vote last year won a vote I'll put that
向我们做广告，投票结果是多少，
in air quotes do you know the tally of
你能告诉我们这里的观众吗？我认为
last year's presidential vote in favor
大约是 100%，不是
of Xi Jinping by the national people's
2,952 比零，是的，这正是我
Congress part of that structure you just
所说的，你找不到几个吗？ 人们
advertised to us what was the vote can
只是为了让它看起来有点甚至一
you tell our audience here I think it's
两个很多这并不奇怪这并不
up to about 100% that doesn't
奇怪2952到
2,952 to zero yes that's exactly what I
零一R中国制度每个人都
said could you not find a few people
支持中国主席那是
just to make it look a little even one
你10秒前刚刚告诉我们有一个
or two many it's not surprising it's not
巨大的系统一个大党一个人
surprising 2952 to
然后你会说，哦，不，但是每个人都
zero one R the Chinese system everyone
支持他，反对他的票数为零，
supports the Chinese president that's
三千人中只有一个人不能说她不是
you just told us 10 seconds ago there's
我的人，如果他是
this huge system a big party one guy and
整个中国共产党的人怎么办，
then you're like oh no but everyone
你永远不知道那是不是 如果是这种
supports him zero votes against him one
情况，那么你的第一个答案就是
person out of 3,000 couldn't say she
多余的，因为如果
jining not my guy one what if he is the
有一亿人都
guy for all the Communist Party of China
必须追随领导人，那并不重要，不，他确实
you never know know well if that's the
在中国人民中赢得了巨大的尊重，
case then your entire first answer is
就像你说尊重一样，我说恐惧，
redundant because it doesn't matter if
你知道吗？  2013年的选票上有很多名字
there's 100 million people they all have
to follow the leader no he does command
huge respect among the Chinese people as
当他们去选举总统时，选票上有多少名字
well as you say respect I say fear do
你能告诉我们的观众 我
you know how many names were on the
认为只有一个候选人 是的，
ballot papers that were given in
没有没有没有其他
2013 how many names were on the ballot
名字是真实的 这是一个真正有安全感的
paper when they went to choose the
领导人，一个知道自己得到
president can you tell our audience I
人民信任的人，你可以投票，
think there is only one candidate yeah
但只能投我，而你们中没有人能
there were no no no other
真正投票反对我，你
names that's a real that's a real secure
不想最终陷入
leader a guy who knows he has the
八年内有六位总理的情况吗？ 是的，所以你
confidence of his people you get to vote
更喜欢独裁统治，不，我们更喜欢一个为
but only for me and none of you can
actually vote against me would you not
中国人民谋福利的制度，我没有
want to end up in a situation with six
说过什么有效或无效，你有巨大的
prime ministers in 8 years yeah so you
经济增长，看看
prefer a dictatorship no we prefer a
独裁统治，没有独裁统治，
system that works for the benefit of the
你刚刚承认有
Chinese people I I have not said a word
选票上没有名字，没有反对他的选票，
about what works or not you got great
他们都跟着他，这就是
economic growth look at the
独裁统治，当你
dictatorship there is no dictatorship M
多次点名发言时，但它是一个
you just admitted that there's no name
独裁者，选票上有多少候选人，有
on the ballot paper no votes against him
多少国王
and they all just follow him that's the
女王，当 国王接替女王
dictatorship Med when you have a say by
name multiple times after but it's a
芭蕾纸上有多少位候选人 有多少位
dictator how many candidates are there
使得英国不是一个民主国家 你
on the ballot paper how many what king
问错人了 我是共和党人所以
Queen when the king succeeds the queen
我认为我们应该成为一个完全的民主国家
how many candidates are there on the
并摆脱 君主制，我可以
ballet paper how many how many does that
说，在这里你不能说在
make Britain not a democracy well you're
中国你不能采取任何行动来反对，
asking the wrong guy I'm a republican so
是的，我可以，实际上我可以走到
I think we should be a full democracy
街上我可以举起标语牌
and get rid of the monarchy and I can
说让我们摆脱查尔斯国王我可以
say that here you can't say that in
在白金汉宫外发起一场完整的抗议，
China you cannot take any action against
在中国你做不到，
that yes I can actually I can go out on
你甚至不能把
the street I can hold up a placard and
别人的名字写在选票上，这就是
say let's get rid of King Charles I can
你的领袖多么不安全，我是一名
create a whole protest outside
律师，以律师的身份我 可以
Buckingham Palace you can't do that in
给你一长串
China you can't even put one other
关于君主制你不能做的事情，
person's name on a ballot paper that's
我不是在争论，我是说我们
how insecure Your Leader is I'm I'm a
有一个民选政府，我们可以
lawyer in my capacity as a lawyer I can
选择，我们可以更换六位
give you a long list of things that you
首相，上帝帮助我们，但我们得到 选择
cannot do regarding the monarchy here in
这个房间里的每个公民，
I'm not debating that I'm saying that we
都可以选择，听着，你最终会得到让
have an elected government we get to
整个国家破产的迷你预算，
choose we get to swap six Prime
这是一个诚实的答案，维克多，
Ministers God help us but we get to pick
但维克多，我很钦佩，因为这是
everyone in this room who's a citizen
一个诚实的答案，你的答案是，这是一个
gets to pick listen you end up with your
至少有效的独裁统治 说
mini budget which bankrupt the whole
不不不你不能继续躲闪
country that's an honest answer Victor
一分钟你说这不是doip然后
but Victor I admire that because that's
我给你看这是你说的但它正在
an honest answer your answer is it's a
起作用我们已经成长了我的选择一个myy
dictatorship that works at least say
如果这是你的观点我会认真地
that no no no you can't you keep dodging
敦促你 做更多关于
one minute you say it's not a doip then
中国制度如何运作的功课好吧让我们
I show you it is you say but it's
谈谈中国制度因为我做了
working we've got growth my pick one myy
一点功课一点功课
if that is your point I will seriously
就是你知道吗
urge you to do more homework about how
习近平把他的名字写进了
the Chinese system works okay let's talk
宪法这很奇怪
about the Chinese system because I did a
领导人 国家主席把自己的名字
little bit of homework a little bit of
写进宪法，而他是国家主席，
homework it's it's it's did you know
没有人这样做过，自从马英九以来，
that Xi Jinping put his name in the
其他中国国家主席都没有这样做过，除了胡因·陶奥，也
Constitution that's weird well the
没有你的老老板邓小平，
leader of the country put his own name
他们都没有这样做过，他们这样做了，还是我错了，
in the Constitution while he's president
错了，呃，没有这样做。 与其他国家相比，中国宪法
no has done that since Ma none of the
修改最频繁，
other Chinese presidents not huin taau
not your old boss Deng Xiao ping none of
我刚才说的话是不是错了？我的
them did it did they or am I wrong it's
名字被写入了宪法，我的
wrong uh did the Chinese Constitution
名字被写入了他当
has been most frequently amended
总统的时候，J的名字被写入了
compared with any other country am I
非总统时期。 他们是现任总统，
wrong about what I just said with my
你知道，告诉我们这里的人群，
name was put into the Constitution I D's
当他们担任总统时，他们
name was put into the while he was
不是自己做的，根据
president and J's name was put into the
记忆，每个人都在
not while they were sitting presidents
领导人
and you know that tell our crowd here
还活着的时候被投入监狱，好吧，所以我是对的，不是
not while they were president they
当他们还是总统时，我喜欢这个
didn't do it themselves according to
小失误，即使是唐纳德·特朗普，
recollection each of were put into the
我们这个时代最伟大的自恋者之一，也没有
cons while they were while the leaders
提议将他的名字写入
were still alive okay so I'm right not
美国宪法，如果你是
while they were president I love the
中国国家主席，你会在没有任何
little slip even Donald Trump one of the
对手的情况下当选，选票上没有名字 纸
great narcissists of our time has not
零票反对你 你把你的名字
proposed yet putting his name into the
写进宪法 六岁的孩子
US Constitution if you are the president
在小学就被教导习近平思想
of China you're elected without any
这不仅仅是
opponents no names on the ballot paper
独裁 这是
zero votes against you you put your name
个人崇拜 我认为中国不相信
in the Constitution six-year-olds are
个人 呃所以为什么 是六岁的孩子
taught about Xi Jinping thought in
了解习近平吗？我
primary school that is not just the
很确定没有六岁的孩子
dictatorship that is a cult of
了解莉兹·特拉斯的迷你
personality I don't think China believes
预算维克多，中国的制度是这样的，
in personal uh so why are six-year-olds
一旦你把国家定向到一个
learning about Xi Jinping thought I'm
方向，每个人都会效仿，他们会
pretty sure no six-year-olds learned
效仿吗 或者他们命令跟随
about Liz truss's mini
他们不跟随选择不，这
budget Victor the Chinese system is such
就像一辆有四个轮子的车辆，在这里你
that once you Orient the country in One
有四个轮子在不同
Direction everyone follows the suit do
方向对齐在中国的方向
they follow or they ordered to follow
汽车的四个轮子都在一个
they don't follow out a choice no it's
方向对齐他们不 展望未来，
like a vehicle with four wheels here you
维克多让我给你举个例子，
have four wheels aligned in different
前
directions in directions in China the
外交部长陈刚被免职，
four wheels of a car all lined up in One
Direction They Don't going forward they
自 2023 年 6 月起就没有在公开场合露面，几个月
don't Victor let me give you an example
后，中国国防部长
former for the Chinese way former
李尚富将军失踪 从公众
foreign minister chin gang was removed
视野中几个月来，现在已经被
from his post and has not been seen in
指控腐败的政党开除，
public since June 2023 a few months
至少有两名部长
later China's defense minister General
去年就失踪了，
Lee Shang Fu disappeared from public
向奥斯卡道歉，失去一名
view for months has now been expelled
部长可能会很不幸，失去
from the party accused of corruption
两名部长是粗心，你不知道吗
that's at least two ministers that
我想说的一点是，
disappeared just in the last year with
中国在处理各种腐败问题上确实是无情的，
apologies to Oscar wild to lose one
甚至在
Minister might be unfortunate to lose
外交部长和国防部长中也是如此。
two is careless is it not do you know
想象一下安东尼·布林和劳埃德·奥斯汀
the point I want to make this means
明天就失踪了，我们不知道
China is really merciless in dealing
他们在哪里，我们从未见过他们
with Corruption of all kinds even among
再说一遍，这不正常，维克多听着，
the foreign minister and defense Min
腐败猖獗，我们怎么知道
imagine Anthony blinkin and Lloyd Austin
他们腐败了，他们就消失了，
just disappeared tomorrow we don't know
where they are we've never seen them
审判在哪里？ 对
again that's not normal Victor listen
corruption is rampant how do we know
they're corrupt they just disappeared
where's the
前者的审判是因为我们甚至不知道
trial the tri finish my point Corruption
他在哪里 很多你不知道的事情
of all kinds in China need to be dwelt
并不意味着不会发生 对
with so where's the trial mercilessness
你只是指控腐败的这个人的审判在哪里
so where's the trial where's the trial
张是我的
of the former for is we don't even know
好朋友 20多年来
where he is many those things you don't
他在哪里然后他参与了腐败他在
know doesn't mean doesn't happen where
哪里而且他很快就和他住在一起了他在哪里
is the trial for this man you're just
维克多无论
accusing of corruption Chang was my good
你的好朋友你都不知道他在哪里
friend for more than 20 years where is
无论外交部长在哪里
he then he is involved in corruption
中国这不是一个
where is he and he is dwelt with very
难题，我们不是问
swiftly where is he Victor regardless of
新张中间的兰的兄弟在哪里，
your good friend you don't know where he
你可以回避失踪的
is regardless of where is the for
中国前外交部长在哪里，
foreign minister of China this is not a
顺便说一句，他没有被
hard question we're not asking where
指控腐败，发言人来了
Ran's brother in the middle of shin Jang
出来并说他有健康原因然后
is that you can dodge where is the
腐败后来发生了
former foreign minister of China who
他去哪里了你的朋友这意味着
disappeared and by the way he wasn't
有一个过程，这个过程
accused of corruption the spokesman came
从一个谎言开始，说他生病了，
out and said he has health reasons then
然后下一个谎言是他腐败了，他可能
corruption came later by the way where
生病了 你永远不知道我的意思是他
did he go your friend that means there
可能在
is a process and the process the process
中国监狱里生病了现在可能生病了你永远不
starts with one lie that he's ill and
知道但至少龚因为腐败而失去了工作
then the next lie is he's corrupt he may
最后一个问题
be ill you never know I mean he's
就是他在哪里他
probably ill after he's been in a
在中国的某个地方你永远不会见到
Chinese prison may be ill now you never
他 他是14亿人中的一员，
know but at least gong lost his job
不，不只是他，还有很多
because of his corruption last question
人失踪了，前
that's the point where is he he's
国防部长失踪了，
somewhere in China you will never see
工业和技术部
him he is among the 1.4 billion people
失踪了，国际刑警组织前
no it's not just him there's many other
主席在中国失踪了，
people who have disappeared the previous
如果他们不喜欢你，你就消失了，这就是
defense minister disappeared the
中国的法治 我很高兴
ministry of industry and Technology
他们消失了，因为如果他们继续
disappeared the former Interpol
做好自己的工作，他们会带来更大的
president disappeared in China you just
好处，要小心你的愿望，因为
disappear if they don't like you that's
每个人都在看这个节目，如果
the rule of law in China I'm so happy
今晚你出了什么问题，如果
they disappear because if they keep
我是啤酒，你可能会消失 我希望你能
doing their job they will bring greater
保释我，
dis be careful what you wish for cuz
我必须先找到你，中国
everyone's watching this show and if you
显然是一个大国，我想
get something wrong tonight maybe you
引进
disappear if I is a beer I hope you will
伦敦大学
bail me
东方非洲研究学院的陈史蒂文·陈（Steven Chan）教授，嗯，习近平习近平
out I'd have to find you first and China
的政策，他对中国的镇压
is apparently a big country um I want to
持不同政见者，我的意思是，中国从来都不是一个
bring in uh Steven Chan professor at the
民主国家，其他总统也都是
University of London's School of
独裁者，但我们是否可以同意，在
Oriental African studies um Stephen XI
jinping's policies his Crackdown on
国内镇压、
dissident I mean China was never a
巩固权力方面，新平处于不同的水平？
democracy other presidents were also
dictatorial but can we agree that
不知道四轮
xinping is on a different level when it
汽车都朝同一个方向行驶 令人高兴的
comes to repression at home the
是，他当然巩固了自己的
consolidation of power I assume you
权力，他是一位非常非常强大的总统，
disagree with Victor's description of
我认为这一切的真正考验
him as part of a I don't know four-wheel
是中国如何对待香港，
car all driving in the same Direction
加大对异议的镇压
Happily he certainly Consolidated his
和自由表达意见，而他们本来
power he is a very very strong president
应该
and I think that the real test of all of
在一个国家两种制度的
this is how China has treated Hong Kong
生活方式中拥有一定程度的自由，但我们
with the increasing clampdown on dissent
在中国看不到任何激烈辩论的证据，
and free expression of opinion when they
我注意到
were meant to have a degree of freedom
我一生中最大的失望之一是 当我
in a one country two system way of
读到中国学术界的作品时，每个人都遵守
approaching life we can't see any
党派路线，没有人进行独立
evidence of vibrant debate in China and
研究来发表，因为它是任何
I note that one of the great
批评的东西，例如不仅仅是甘
disappointments of my life is when I
平，任何批评中国
read Chinese acad mic works everyone TOS
外交政策的东西，否则他们可能会消失，
a party line no one does independent
无论如何他们都可能不会得到晋升
research to publish as it were anything
拉汉 阿萨特是
critical of for instance not just Gan
大西洋理事会国际
ping anything critical about Chinese
人权法高级研究员拉汉，我们在第一部分中
foreign policy or they might disappear
深入讨论了2014年对
they might not get promoted in any case
威尔斯的镇压和你个人的
rahan assat is a senior fellow at the
情况，习近平私下
Atlantic Council international human
呼吁全面打击
rights law rahan in part one we' talked
恐怖主义，并表明
in depth about uh the repression against
访问新庄后绝对毫不留情，
the weers and your own personal
你认为习近平在多大程度上
situation in 2014 Xi Jinping privately
推动了新庄发生的事情，
called for an allout struggle quote
你认为他对中国的镇压负有多大责任？
against terrorism and to show absolutely
no mercy after a visit to shinjang how
事实是，所有这一切都是
much do you believe Xi Jinping is
在现任政府的权力下发生的
driving what's happening in Shin Jang
很多学者都把这件事归咎于
how much do you think he's responsible
他，这件事发生在他的统治时期，他是
for the repression in China well the
那个说绝对不留情的人，
matter of the fact is that all of it
铲除ERS的根枝，
happened under current Administration
打破他们的联系，
right so many scholars are attributing
这些都是在他领导下实施的政策，
to him it happened under his Reign he's
所以很难将
the one who said absolutely no mercy um
习近平分开 来自当前
stamping out roots and branches of the
政策的ping 马丁·杰克（Martin Jake）的
ERS breaking out their connection and
畅销书《当中国统治
these are the policies implemented under
世界》的作者，你听到维克多（Victor）
his leadership so it's very hard to
说得好，我们不能成为独裁国家，
separate XI Jin ping from the current
因为我们做得很好，经济
policy shinan Martin Jake's author of
表现惊人，我们没有 莉兹相信
the best selling book when China rules
迷你预算等等，但随后你就陷入了
the world you you heard Victor talk
关于独裁和
about well we can't be a dictatorship
增长能否共存的争论，你是否需要
because we're doing so well the economy
民主来与之并存，我
is doing amazing we don't have Liz trust
想到了大流行病，马丁和我
mini budgets Etc but then you get into
认为中国对大流行病的反应
the debate about can dictatorship and
是独裁统治的地方
growth coexist do you need to have
缺乏透明度，
democracy to go alongside that and I
失踪事件困扰着中国，
think about the pandemic Martin and I
因为
think about China's reaction to the
中国的审查
pandemic is that where the dictatorship
方法当然存在黑洞，其严厉的政策，零
the lack of transparency the
二氧化碳政策，镇压导致一些
disappearances caught up with China
人说，我们看到了超过一百两百万人的
because of course there was a black hole
死亡，我们在中国看到了抗议活动
in China in terms of China's censorship
人们尖叫的那一刻，
methods its Draconian policies the zero
中国实际上与现实发生了冲突，并
Co policy the Crackdown which led some
说这个制度无法
people say to over a million two million
长期生存，我请求在
deaths we saw protests in buildings
大流行问题上持不同意见，因为
people screaming was that a moment where
实际上在2020年和
China actually collided with reality and
2021年的两年里，中国确实做到了这一点 在这种
said this system it it can't survive
情况下，表现非常好，而且
longterm well I beg to differ okay on
表现优于西方，
the question of the pandemic because
其原因非常复杂，呃，你
actually for two years uh uh uh 2020 and
必须考虑一种非常不同的
2021 actually China did under the
系统，现在讨论的问题之一，
circumstances extremely well and Well
我认为，呃呃，到目前为止，关于
outperformed the West and the reasons
这个问题是 呃，如果你说独裁者专制所有这些，这个国家
for it are quite complicated uh you've
听起来好像这个国家不起作用，
got to take into a very different kind
of system now one of the problems with
但如果你说不是你
the discussion I think uh uh so far on
个人，而是有人说没有
this question is that uh the country it
讨论，这是我认为这
sounds as if the country doesn't work if
绝对是不真实的，所以我们' 我们
you say dictator despot all these
在这里展示的不是准确的
I but if and and you say not you
图片，这不是关于
personally but and one says there's no
准确的图片，而是关于平衡，
discussion this is I think this is
所以我不否认你
absolutely untrue so what we're
所说的，但你是英国人，你会
presenting here is not an accurate
认为这是一场政治地震，如果
picture we've got it's not about
外交大臣和
accurate picture it's about balance
国防部长在六个月内失踪了，
right so I I don't deny what you're
没有被捕，肯定消失了，
saying but you're British you would
是的，而且
think it was a political earthquake if
看起来有些东西，清功
the foreign secretary and the defense
也是我的朋友，我不知道
secretary disappeared in the space of
他发生了什么事，我认为这
six months not arrested disappeared
当然很奇怪 在我们看来，
surely yeah yeah and and there is
这种情况的发生很奇怪，但是呃，但我认为
something on look Ching gong was was a
问题是，当我们谈论中国时，我们必须尝试
friend of mine as well and I don't know
超越纸板剪裁，
what's happened to him and I think it is
并了解它是
odd certainly to our eyes it's we weird
如何真正运作的，好吧，让我们
that this can happen but uh but I think
引入我们的 一直
that the thing is that we've got to try
在伦敦康威大厅等候的观众，我要
and get Beyond cardboard cutouts when
去找第四排的那位女士，是
we're talking about China and understand
的，你，
how it really works okay um let's bring
我的问题是，作为香港的持不同政见者，我
in our audience who've been waiting here
知道我无法
in London's Conway Hall I'm going to go
在香港或香港自由表达。 英国，不要让
to the yes the lady there on the fourth
其他人陷入麻烦，我也
row yes you
知道你刚才声称
my question is as a disident from Hong
中国有言论自由，现在
Kong knowing that I cannot express
可以再次批评中国
freely in Hong Kong or in the UK without
政府，你能
risking other people in trouble I also
证明一下言论自由，并告诉我们施
know that you just now made claims about
平犯的两个最严重的错误是什么吗？
there's free speech in China and it's
在过去的五年里，这是一个很好的问题，如果
possible to criticize the Chinese
你能向我们证明，
government just now again can you please
批评中国
demonstrate that free speech and tell us
政府和中国是可以的，甚至只是说
what are siin Ping's two worst mistakes
她有点像赢得了便便，这对
in the past five years great question if
我来说就足够了，谢谢你，
you can demonstrate to us that it's okay
维克多，你想接受吗？
to criticize shping the Chinese
很好的问题，谢谢，我想说，呃，中国
government and China or even just say
需要采取更迅速的
she kind of resembles winning the Poo
行动来应对
will be good enough for me thank you
中国急剧的人口老龄化和
Victor do you want to take that question
人口急剧下降，你
well thank you I would say uh China need
认为习近平应对
to make more prompt uh take more prompt
老龄化问题的速度不够快是罪魁祸首吗？ 不，我认为呃，
actions in dealing with the dramatic uh
整个中国政府，包括
aging population in China and the
中央国务院
dramatic uh demographic decline do you
地方政府，需要迅速采取行动，
think XI Jin Ping's to blame for not
扭转这个严重的呃
being fast enough on Aging no I think uh
人口老龄化问题，
the whole Chinese government including
我们不会受到
the Central Committee State council
VI的批评，让我们回到观众呃
local government need to take actions
让我们去找那位打领带的绅士
quickly to reverse that dramatic uh
是的，是的，是的，是的，亚历克斯，对不起，亚历克斯·文，
aging population problem and demographic
一些查塔姆房子，我的问题是呃
we're not going to get a criticism out
债务，所以发生了非常严重的骚乱，
of VI let's go back to the audience uh
例如肯尼亚的新闻报道，
let's go to the gentleman here in the
导致问题的一些债务
tie yes you yeah Alex sorry Alex Vin
是欠下的 对中国来说，问题
some chatam house my my question is uh
是中国呃将如何应对日益
debt so there's been very bad riots for
增加的呃债务
example it's been in the news in Kenya
取消压力呃今年至少有17个非洲
some of that debt that's causing the
国家特别困难，
problem is owed to China so the question
is is how is China uh going to handle
谢谢我了解中国在
the increasing uh pressures for debt
这些大规模呃互联互通
cancellation uh at least 17 African
项目中的债务只是一个 占
countries are in particular distress
国家债务总额的一小部分，因为他们欠
this year thank
美国、英国、
you I understand the Chinese debt in
国际金融
these large scale uh connectivity
机构等的债务，他们不仅
projects is only a small portion of the
欠中国，还欠许多其他国家，
overall national debt because they own
这就是现实。 其次，有人
debt to the United States to Britain to
指责死亡陷阱，这是
the international uh financing uh
完全错误和虚假，因为如果
institutions Etc they not just own debt
你想做连接项目，
to China but to many other countries
重大项目融资，你需要
that's the reality secondly there is
拥有股权和债务，债务是
accusation about the death trap which is
包装中不可或缺的一部分好吧，
completely wrong and false because if
让我们回到观众，嗯，我先让
you want to do connectivity project
这位先生们休息一下，然后去
major project finance things you need to
后面我们去找那位先生，
have Equity as well as debt debt is an
下
indispensable part of the packaging okay
一位是你，我的名字是索南·弗拉齐（Sonam frazzi），我
let's go back to the audience um I Sate
想问你一个关于
this gentlemen the time then go to the
西藏的问题。在中国入侵西藏之前，我出生在西藏，
back then we go to that gentleman there
不幸的是，
you next after this
自那以后，有 120 万藏人死亡，
one my name is Sonam frazzi I would like
我们已经
to ask you a question on
我的问题是西藏经过74
Tibet I was born in Tibet before the
年的中国统治仍然处于
Chinese invasion of Tibet unfortunately
封锁状态，没有记者，没有个人
1.2 million Tibetans have died since and
游客，甚至连藏人都
we have been made
不允许与家人见面，
refugees my question is Tibet after 74
中国害怕什么，对西藏进行
years of Chinese rule is still under
如此严格的控制，而藏人又是
lockdown no journalists no individual
如此 先生，自联合国王朝以来，我们自己的国家就存在着不人道的存在，
tourists no even Tibetans are not
allowed to see their families what is
甚至更早，西藏
China afraid of to keep keep Tibet in
经过不同的朝代，
such a tight control and Tibetans is
不同的历史时期，一直是中国的一部分，
such a inhuman existence in our own
我可以向你保证，在你
country sir ever since the UN Dynasty if
和我的一生中，西藏将永远是中国的一部分，
not even earlier Tibet has been part of
为什么你如此坚持 关于
China through different dynasties
不想被中国统治的统治地方，
different historical period
没有西藏，我们去过西藏，
I can assure you during your lifetime
台湾他们对
and mine Tibet will always be part of
新江不满意，西藏成为中国的一部分
China why are you so insistent on ruling
并不取决于你是否喜欢，
places that don't want to be ruled by
这是一个大趋势 我们的时代是一个大
China no Tibet we've been through Tibet
趋势，你需要接受这一点，然后
Taiwan they're not happy in
你才能自由地回到
shinjang Tibet being part of China
中国访问西藏，
doesn't depend on whether you like it or
你听起来像是在威胁那
not it's a mega trend of our time a mega
个人，不，我不是，他说你必须
Trend and you need to accept that before
接受这一点，然后你才能回去，他是
you will feel free to go back to
从那个地方你可以在英国和平地生活，
China visit Tibet
这很好，但他是难民，
you sound like you're threatening the
但如果你想回到西藏，
man no I'm not he said you have to
承认西藏是中国时期的一部分，
accept that before you can go back he's
如果他不这样做，他就不能
from that place you live in peace in
回到他的家，你也不能去
Britain that's good but he's a refugee
回来，因为中国不想看到
but if you want to go back to Tibet
任何人主张
acknowledge Tibet is part of China
西藏独立，为什么不可能，那永远不会
period And what if he doesn't he can't
发生，维克多，为什么
go back to his home you cannot go
中国不能依靠自己的优点，为什么
back because China doesn't want to see
我们要进行欺凌和威胁
anyone advocating for the independence
把你打碎 台湾 你不能
of Tibet why can't no way there will
回去，除非你签署这份文件，或者
that will never happen Victor why can't
声明为什么不安全
China rest on its own merits why the
世界第二大经济体
bullying and the threats we're going to
你听起来如此不安全 中国安全
break you to pieces Taiwan you can't go
基于
back until you sign this document or
只有一个中国和台湾是一部分的原则
that declar why the insecurity second
中国的西藏是中国的一部分，成江
biggest economy in the world major power
是中国时期的一部分，即使
you sound so insecure China security
那里的人们不想成为其中的一部分，
rests on the principle that there is
你也不在乎，大多数
only one China and Taiwan is part of
人都像中国人一样生活得很幸福。
China Tibet is part of China and Shing
投票 我会和你一起去，
Jang is part of China period And even if
我们要去西藏，
the people there don't want to be part
我们要和所有藏人交谈 我
of it you don't give a damn the majority
可以去西藏，但来自
of the people live happily as Chinese
那里的人不能去那里，
ciens did you do a vote I will go with
当你这么说时，你听起来很可笑 抱歉，
you to we're going to go to Tibet and
让我们回到后面的观众席，
we're going to talk to all the Tibetan I
然后这位先生，我的
can go to Tibet but the guy who's from
名字是伊萨·阿伦（Isa alun），我是英国乌尔人，
there can't go there you sound ludicrous
除了
when you say this stuff I'm sorry to say
跑步，我对许多乌尔侨民的问题，
let us go back to audience gentle at the
back and then this gentleman here my
我们不被允许
name is a Isa alun I am a British Ur
联系
except
自从
ran and my question for many in the U
2017 年中国政府开始将
diaspora
超过 300 万 ERS ​​人关押
we have not been allowed
到他们的高科技监视
contact with our families at home visin
集中营以来，我们的家人就一直在乌拉尔自治区
the UR autonomous region since
2017 when Chinese government started
detaining more than 3 million plus ERS
为什么我们不能
into their Hightech surveillance
和我们的家人自由地交谈呢？
concentration camps my question to you
好吧，又一个，又一个，这么多
sir what's the Chinese government trying
赌注，同样的故事，同样的问题，
to hide from us
我总是很高兴看到无论我
second okay why can't we why can't we
走到哪里，都是一个 wegle 人，因为我确实将
not talk freely with our families
The Wiggles 视为我的兄弟姐妹
okay another yet another weager so many
在一个条件下，我的一部分开始
Wagers the same story the same questions
为你真正的兄弟姐妹感到难过，
I'm always very happy to see Wherever I
我会在
Go a wegle person because I do consider
一对一的情况下诚实，尽管 Wiggles 需要
The Wiggles as my brothers and sisters
承认 Shin Jang 是中国的一部分，
on one condition part of me starting to
如果你不接受这一点，这是一个很大的先决条件
feel sorry for your actual brothers and
前提你
sisters I'll be honest on one on one on
不是我的兄弟姐妹坚持住，这样他就
one condition though Wiggles need to
可以了，你们不必是
acknowledge that Shin Jang is part of
兄弟姐妹，但是他能不能不
China that's a big precondition if you
和他的家人说话，这取决于你的
do not accept that precondition you are
家人在哪里，确实有一个
not my brother or sister hold on so he
分裂分子想要宣扬
that's fine you don't have to be
分裂主义 Wiggle 的转，
brothers and sisters but can he not talk
那些不分离的人怎么样？消失吧，
to his family it depends on where your
把 Shin Jang 变成东突厥斯坦，这
family is there are indeed a wo
永远不会发生，听这个电话，
separatists who want to promote
你的朋友
separatism of Wiggle turn what about the
坚持一项 CH 政策，他只想通过
people who are not separ just disappear
电话与家人交谈，
turn Shin Jang into East turkistan this
几年我 没有和我妈妈说话
will never happen listen to this call
我想和我妈妈说话 我是
your friends
英国人 我想和我妈妈说话
to stick to the one CH policy he just
你理解字面上的意思吗 支持一项
wants to talk on the phone to a family
对华政策支持是中国
member years I didn't speak to my mother
胜利时期的一部分 你难道不忍心看
I want to speak to my mother I am
到这个人吗？ 不要和他82
British I want to speak to my mother do
岁的母亲分开说话，我希望你的母亲
you understand literally support One
在这个大厅里和你谈谈，为什么
China policy support being part of China
你让她走，也许她可以，但
Victor period do you have no heart to
在中国有一个条件，对
see this man who can't speak to his 82y
任何分裂主义运动零容忍82岁的
old mother separ I wish your mother is
女人是一个 对中国的威胁
here in this Hall talking to you and why
这对中国意味着什么 我希望她不是
you let her go maybe she could but then
分裂主义者 但如果她是分裂主义者 在我们结束之前她
on one condition in China Zero Tolerance
将被法律时期维克多居住
of any separatist movement 82 year- old
我有一个问题要问
woman is a threat to China what does
你 我们在英国 我们在康威大厅
that say about China I hope she's not a
历史悠久的言论自由协会，我们可以做一个这样的
separatist but if she's a separatist she
节目吗？我可以
will be dwelt with by law period Victor
像这样采访你吗？rahan 可以参加
before we finish I have one question for
北京这样的一个小组吗，比如北京
you we're in the UK we're in Conway Hall
国际会议中心，我们可以
historic Free Speech Society could we do
做一个这样的节目吗？观众可以
a show like this could I interview you
自由提问，你可以提问
like this could rahan come be on a panel
来自所有人 没有人经过审查 没有人
like this in Beijing in say the Beijing
受到威胁 我们可以在北京这样做吗
International Convention Center can we
如果你让我列出所有的
do a show like this audience members
支持 你真的会这么做 我可以向
freely ask questions you take questions
你保证，一场每个
from everyone no one's vetted no one's
观众都可以自由发言的节目 没有
threatened could we do this in Beijing
人出现 他们的房子后来
medy if you ask me to line up all the
很多欧洲国家你
support you will do that really I can
不需要签证去中国拿起你的
assure you that a show where every
行李买票问我不是要求
audience member gets to speak freely No
外国人维克多要求外国人
One turns up at their house afterwards
来我是说中国观众可以
for many European countries you do not
出现并问他们想要的东西吗 想
need a visa to go to China pick up your
批评习近平批评
luggage buy a ticket ask I'm not asking
政府问你问题谈论我们
foreigners Victor asking foreigners to
可以在北京做吗在
come I'm saying could a Chinese audience
中国不要批评我们的总统所以
turn up and ask whatever they want
我们不能这样做除非你很高兴
criticize Xi Jinping criticize the
你从马的批评中提出积极的建设性建议
government ask you questions talk about
weers could you do it in Beijing m in
嘴上不要批评，除非它是正确的
China don't criticize our president so
不是唯一的目标具有
we couldn't do this unless you have glad
建设性目的的批评将是更好的
you positive constructive proposal to
言论自由言论自由是我们
make from criticism from the horse's
在这个节目中珍惜的目标我很高兴为
mouth don't criticize unless it's posi
您提供一个言论自由的平台我
is not the only goal criticism with
希望您能提供 我回来了，维克多·
constructive purposes will be a better
加尔，谢谢您抽出时间，感
free speech free speech is goal we
谢康威厅的观众，
cherish on this show I'm glad to have
感谢家里的每个人观看
offered you a platform for free speech I
这一集的《头 10》
wish you could offer me one back Victor
gal thank you for your time thank you to
the audience in Conway Hall and thank
you to everyone at home for watching
this episode of head 10
[Music]
[Applause]